<idea-plugin>
    <id>com.qrowsolutions.stack-doctor</id>
    <name>Stack Doctor</name>
    <vendor email="qrowsolutions@gmail.com" url="https://github.com/Wayto0blivion/Stack-Doctor">Qrow Solutions</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
        <h2>Stack Doctor — Docker Compose service map &amp; network doctor</h2>
        <p>
            Turns a <code>docker-compose.yml</code> into a visual <b>service dependency map</b> and runs
            a set of <b>"doctor" checks</b> for the networking mistakes that waste hours:
        </p>
        <ul>
            <li>Service dependency graph (<code>depends_on</code> / shared networks)</li>
            <li>Ports published to <code>127.0.0.1</code> that won't be reachable from other devices</li>
            <li>Missing healthchecks on services other containers depend on</li>
            <li>Suspicious / non-existent host volume paths</li>
            <li><code>depends_on</code> pointing at services that don't exist, and dependency cycles</li>
            <li>Missing <code>env_file</code> references</li>
            <li>Ports that are <code>expose</code>d internally vs actually published</li>
        </ul>
        <h2>Getting started</h2>
        <ol>
            <li>
                <b>Install &amp; open a project.</b> Stack Doctor works in any JetBrains IDE
                (IntelliJ IDEA, PyCharm, WebStorm, GoLand, Rider, and more). Open a project that
                contains at least one Compose file &mdash; anything named like
                <code>docker-compose.yml</code>, <code>compose.yaml</code>, or a
                <code>*.yml</code>/<code>*.yaml</code> file with <code>compose</code> in its name.
                They're discovered automatically; there's nothing to configure.
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>Open the tool window.</b> Go to <code>View | Tool Windows | Stack Doctor</code>
                (it docks on the right). You'll see every Compose file as a root node, with its
                services branching to the right and <code>depends_on</code> arrows showing what
                starts before what.
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>Read the diagnosis.</b> Findings are listed below the map and highlighted inline
                in the YAML editor. Nodes tint amber or red when a service &mdash; or a whole file
                &mdash; has warnings or errors, so problem areas stand out at a glance.
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>Drill in.</b> Click any node for a line-by-line breakdown of its configuration
                and issues; double-click to jump straight to it in the editor. Not sure what a
                symbol, line, or colour means? Hit <b>Legend</b> in the toolbar.
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>Fix it.</b> Apply the inline quick-fixes on highlighted YAML (bind a port to all
                interfaces, declare a missing volume or network, and more), or click
                <b>Add healthchecks</b> to generate context-aware healthchecks for the services
                that need one.
            </li>
        </ol>
        <p>
            Press the <b>Refresh</b> button in the tool window anytime to re-scan the project and
            re-run every check.
        </p>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <h3>0.3.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Merged preview.</b> A new <b>Merged preview</b> button combines any two compose files into one &mdash; pick a base (defaults to <code>docker-compose.yml</code>) and an overlay (e.g. <code>docker-compose.override.yml</code>) and see the effective configuration Docker would run, with the doctor checks re-run on the merged result and overlay-contributed values highlighted.</li>
            <li><b>Collapsible warnings &amp; errors.</b> The diagnostics list at the bottom now has a header you can click to collapse it out of the way and expand it again.</li>
            <li><b>Draggable nodes.</b> Drag service and file nodes to rearrange the map; the dependency arrows follow, and your layout is kept until you press <b>Reset layout</b> (or restart the IDE).</li>
            <li><b>Add fields from the service form.</b> The edit form now has an <b>Add field</b> button to add parameters a service doesn't have yet &mdash; healthcheck, restart policy, expose, and more &mdash; then fill them in and Save. Long field hints now wrap instead of being clipped at the popup edge.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.2.1</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>The service edit form now includes an editable <b>Healthcheck</b> field, so a generated healthcheck can be tweaked in place.</li>
            <li>Fixed edit-form fields being clipped on the right edge &mdash; they now fit the popup and resize with it.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.2.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Edit services right from the map.</b> Click a service node to open an editable form for its parameters &mdash; image, ports, expose, depends_on, volumes, networks, env files, environment and restart &mdash; and Save writes the changes straight back into the compose file in one undoable step.</li>
            <li>The map legend now describes what each service category is for, instead of repeating the same note.</li>
            <li>Updated for the latest JetBrains IDEs; now supports 2025.3 and newer.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.1.1</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>New plugin logo and tool-window icon.</li>
            <li>Fixed the map background flashing over a custom IDE background image &mdash; the map now overlays the IDE background directly instead of painting a solid fill behind the nodes.</li>
            <li>Added a "Getting started" guide to the plugin description.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.1.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Initial release: whole-project Compose service map with dependency layout.</li>
            <li>Ten networking "doctor" checks, surfaced inline and in the tool window.</li>
            <li>Context-aware healthcheck generation (bulk, per-service, and as a quick-fix).</li>
            <li>Map colours now follow the active IDE theme.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <!-- Provided by all JetBrains IDEs -->
    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends>org.jetbrains.plugins.yaml</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <toolWindow
            id="Stack Doctor"
            anchor="right"
            icon="/icons/toolWindow.svg"
            factoryClass="com.qrowsolutions.stackdoctor.ui.StackDoctorToolWindowFactory"/>

        <notificationGroup id="Stack Doctor" displayType="BALLOON"/>

        <localInspection
            language="yaml"
            shortName="StackDoctorCompose"
            displayName="Docker Compose problems (Stack Doctor)"
            groupName="Docker"
            enabledByDefault="true"
            level="WARNING"
            implementationClass="com.qrowsolutions.stackdoctor.inspection.ComposeDoctorInspection"/>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <action
            id="StackDoctor.Refresh"
            class="com.qrowsolutions.stackdoctor.actions.RefreshAction"
            text="Refresh Stack Doctor"
            description="Re-scan the project for Compose files and re-run diagnostics."/>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
